

## TECHNICAL LEADERSHIP · TECHNOLOGY CONSULTING

☆ Columbus, OH | 
igor@fer.st | 
igorfer.st | 
igorfe

Summary\_

Experienced technologist with a track record of high-impact roles at growth-stage software companies and as an independent consultant.

Deep and diverse skill set spanning full-stack development, product management, engineering management, machine learning, and technical training.

Domain expertise in healthcare, capital markets, and insurance.

# Work Experience

Rational Form, Ltd. Columbus, OH

OWNER Apr. 2016 - present

- Owner of technology consulting and custom software development business. I use strategic product thinking and deep technical expertise to help my clients meet business goals by leveraging modern software tools.
- Projects include web front-end for a consumer product safety and performance testing tool, back-end API design, and staff augmentation for a high-growth, VC-backed tech company.
- Manage all aspects of client engagements from weekly status reports to billing, operations, and subcontracting.

Root Insurance Columbus, OH

Senior Software Engineer Sept. 2018 - present

- Multiple high-impact projects at a high-growth insuretech startup, including expanding insurance business to new markets, enhancing end-user mobile app, and using machine learning to improve the accuracy of insurance rates.
- Python SME for engineering and data science teams.
- Assist data science team with defining and planning engineering work to support scaling data science across the company.

Aver Inc. Columbus, OH

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sept. 2014 - Feb. 2018

- Led the cross-functional team that built Aver's Virtual Payer, a care management and revenue cycle management product for surgical centers. My team took this product from idea to production application with paying customers.
- Owned product design and technical architecture, maintained product roadmap, implemented APIs and features.
- Grew developer team from 4 to 13: overhauled interview process to emphasize rigor and consistency, defined onboarding process and personally onboarded most new developers. Coached two direct reports through promotion to senior engineer.
- Introduced and trained engineering team on new technologies (Docker, Angular), development processes (TDD, code reviews, release process) and agile methodology (user stories, estimation).

**InSample Inc.**San Francisco, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Mar. 2014 - Sept. 2014

- First employee at healthcare analytics startup building a web-based tool for data exploration and statistical de-biasing of clinical experiments; designed and built the product protoype together with the CTO.
- Prepared fundraising materials and interviewed prospective customers.

Google Inc.

Mountain View, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2013 - Mar. 2014

- Implemented a novel conversion tracking visualization (patent pending) for the AdWords suite of analytics tools.
- Acted as Angular SME during team's transition from legacy front-end framework to Angular.
- Researched and recommended enhancements to Google Analytics machine-learning algorithm for attribution modeling.

## Palantir Technologies Inc.

Palo Alto, CA

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT ANALYST / SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2011 - Jan. 2013

- Embedded with a prominent global macro hedge fund, the largest customer for Palantir's capital markets analytics platform.
- Conducted user interviews and gathered product requirements to help drive product development based on market needs.
- Product owner for platform's visualization and reporting features.
- Transitioned to engineering team to implement visualization and reporting feature roadmap.

November 25, 2018 Igor Ferst · Résumé

# **Technology**

Languages/Frameworks Python, Ruby/Rails, Javascript/Angular/React/Node.JS, Java

**Infrastructure** AWS, Docker, Ansible, SQL

**Machine Learning** Random forests, vector-based NLP, Markov chains

# Patents\_

2015 Radial display generation and interactive system, Google Inc. (pending)

2018 Systems and methods for providing episode-based medical care, Aver Inc. (in preparation)

## **Education**

Cornell University Ithaca, NY

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- PhD candidate in Applied Mathematics supported by a National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship.
- Published original research on probabilistic optimization algorithms: https://tinyurl.com/ycheu4us

#### **University of Waterloo**

Waterloo, Ontario

M.MATH. IN COMBINATORICS & OPTIMIZATION

### **University of Chicago**

Chicago, IL

**B.S. IN MATHEMATICS WITH HONORS** 

# **Volunteering**

Tech Elevator Columbus, OH

• Panelist and student mentor for local software developer bootcamp.

#### **United Schools Network**

Columbus, OH

- Multiple years volunteering for a local charter school network.
- · Designed and taught a three month after-school programming course for middle-school students.
- Developed spreadsheet-based operational tools for school administrators.

## Columbus Arts Festival Columbus, OH

- Member of organizing committee for 2016 and 2017 festivals.
- Created an interactive on-line festival map: https://github.com/igorferst/columbus-arts-festival-map
- Interviewed vendors for mobile app development.